Hey, investors, good morning, good afternoon, and good evening.
Wherever you are in the world right now, my
name is AJ Dent, Principal Owner of Take Notes
Capital Real Estate Investing Company, and over the next
few minutes, I want to break down a strategy
to where you can invest in real estate, earn
real estate returns.
Backed by the property.
without ever actually owning it.
Now, this is without the tenants, without the maintenance
calls, without the contractors, any of those headaches.
But before I jump into the bells and whistles,
I want to take a second to express my
gratitude.
I just want to say thank you.
You can be doing almost a thousand different things
right now, but you've decided to kindly show up,
kind of see what's going on here, and see
if this is a good fit for you.
So I do hope you find value in this
video.
As mentioned, my name is AJ Dent, I'm from
Vicksburg, Mississippi.
Currently living in Boston, Massachusetts, and my journey into
real estate actually started in life insurance.
Through sales, networking, partnerships, I was able to move
into the nuclear contracting industry, W2 lifestyle, and part-time,
I was investing in real estate.
Crossed over a million in acquisitions through wholesaling.
educated real estate agents nationwide on how to profit
through Notes, and I actually created Notes through creative
financing.
These were seller finance transactions, sub-to's.
wraps, lease options, which helped me execute over 30+
Notes since 2023, and I'm extremely grateful for that
experience, and I'm glad I built the relationships I
did.
So, what is mortgage note investing, right?
How does it work?
Most investors, even today, don't even know this strategy
exists.
So, I buy distressed mortgages
from banks.
These are delinquent loans where borrowers aren't paying their
mortgage.
I take over the bank's seat, I reach out
to the borrower, figure out the problem going on,
and I just simply find a way path forward.
And get those borrowers back on their feet, and
simultaneously earn cash flow at the same time.
So we're earning passive income through mortgage debt secured
by the actual property.
As you know, most investors are out buying the
properties, dealing with the headaches.
Hey, we got it on easy mode over here.
We're just buying the debt behind the property, okay?
So, I want to talk about the strategy.
How do we get in front of these notes?
One lane, one focus, we don't flip houses, we
flip paper, baby.
So, we buy non-performing notes, first lien position only,
non-performing, usually about 3 months behind.
working with property values between $50,000 to $500,000, and
these are owner-occupied, single-family residential homes.
We're acquiring these notes to steep discounts, and we're
sourcing these notes directly from banks, some hedge funds,
and…
Sometimes you may have a private investor who may
have a note that they're selling, or
Have their own portfolio that they want to get
rid of a few notes, right?
Now, our markets span across 10 different states.
This is a mix between our primary market and
our secondary market, and I really enjoy these because
they give us our three core values, which is
strong population growth.
Favorable foreclosure timelines, and deep distress inventory, alright?
So I want to talk about what is a
mortgage note.
I really want to break down how we can
get into mortgage note investing.
So, this is a case study, and this is
from a partner.
Her name is Judy.
She bought this note from a local community bank
in South Carolina, or excuse me, there.
Bought this from a local community bank in South
Carolina.
She bought this back in April 2026, got this
for about $22,258.
Now, that's a discounted price.
The borrower is still owed
$28,577.
She didn't pay the price that it was owed,
she paid a discounted price, and it's mainly because
the banks wanted that loan
gone.
So they were willing to sell it at a
discount.
to create new loans and recycle their money.
So what Judy did, she worked through a servicing
company, reached out to the borrower, got them back
active again, and started earning $635 per month in
cash flow.
That's a 33% ROI.
Awesome, right?
Who wouldn't want an extra $635 a month?
So, Judy's in the lien holder position.
That means if the borrower stops paying, she does
have the right.
to foreclose.
Now, I want to mention that we aren't wearing
the landlord hat here, right?
We're not dealing with tenants, toilets, vacancies, repairs, anything
like that.
We're lien lords.
We're working on monthly cash flow, coming in per
month, first lien position, got built-in equity from that
discounted pricing, and we have more than one strategy
to figure out a resolution for the borrower.
But none of this would be possible
without our partners, alright?
So these are the individuals who help us get
closer to the finish line.
Covey Financial, these guys are our servicing companies, handle
communication with the borrower, handle payments coming in from
the borrower.
Handle compliance to make sure everything is legal and
accurate.
National Association of Realtors.
This is a group of over 55,000+ realtors across
the nation, across major markets.
They help with our BPO reports, property valuations, they're
our boots on the grounds.
They help us even sell properties if we, sell
a property through a foreclosure or so.
Reva Global is our virtual assistants team out of
the Philippines to help with the back-end stuff, most
of the due diligence for organization.
emails, even Excel spreadsheets, love those guys.
Legal League, these individuals help us find attorneys in
the state we're acquiring notes from, if we can't
find an attorney through our servicing company.
Ross Diversified is our insurance.
In the event that that property is affected by
the borrower or an act of God, like a
hurricane or tree limb fell… a tree fell on
it, anything crazy, we work through Ross Diversified.
They help us get that property squared away so
we can get to our next step.
Clear 2 Close, title and escrow, these guys are
great.
paperwork, making sure everything's squared away to actually close
on the note, making sure that our due diligence
is accurate.
They dot our I's, cross our T's, they make
sure we're good to go.
So, even with our partners being able to help
us get closer to that finish line, we understand
a little bit about how a note works, but
what's the actual resolution part, right?
How do we get closer to making the money?
So, the goal isn't to bet on one borrower
outcome.
We have 10 different ways to resolve that borrower.
And 3 outcomes is where we focus, alright?
So we don't want any dead ends.
Now, most borrowers fall in 3 buckets.
The first bucket are our re-performers.
These are our loan modifications, forbearance, DPOs, these are
our most profitable situations, which usually 50% of borrowers
fall in.
The other 25% in voluntary exits.
These are ideal cash for keys, where we're trying
to figure out a way to move forward, can't
really meet in the middle, but they may be
open to exiting the property, right?
If they don't want a foreclosure on their credit
for 7 years or so, they may be open
for a cash for keys.
Alright, so 25% foreclosures.
There are times where we do have to foreclose,
and these are individuals who are a little bit
harder to deal with.
They don't want to give up, you know, working
with us.
They are harder to deal with.
Maybe we have to foreclose, and we take the
property back as an REO.
Or, if the market makes sense, and we do
have to take the property back as REO, we
can turn it into a rental property.
But the goal is simple.
We want to rehab the borrower before we have
to foreclose.
So, this is a case study I really want
to touch on.
This one's out of Haker Heights, Texas.
This one was one of those re-performers I talked
about, that 50% range, where we bought this for
$22,533 with the owner still occupied.
They still owed a balance of about $41,548 to
the bank.
So we reached out to the servicing companies, Covey,
for example, they helped us get communication started with
the borrower.
That was about $97.
And from there, we figured out that the borrower
was behind due to medical issues.
Now, we understand life happens, it throws curveballs, so
we worked out a resolution, helped the borrower get
back on track to keep their home, and that
generated cash flow of about $353 per month.
Which was about that 18% ROI.
That's… that's great.
That's almost like a rental property, right?
So, just want to preface here, no rehab, no
tenant.
No title issues with this one, nothing was… no
boots on the ground, nada.
Nothing.
We're still lien holders here.
In the event that the borrower was to fall
behind, we can't figure out a Plan B or
Plan C, we do have the right to foreclose.
So another case study here out of Georgia bought
this one for $24,757, and the unpaid balance was
about $68,573.
The property value here was about $110,000, so it
was a little bit of a spread there.
Now, working through our servicing company, we figured out
that the borrower was behind almost 16 months due
to a job loss, and obviously that is unfortunate,
so once again, figured out a resolution.
Come to find out that the borrower had a
family member that stepped in to help settle the
remaining debt, that $68,000 I mentioned.
Now, once we negotiated that debt, that got us
to about $41,000 they were able to pay off,
which was 68% of the remaining balance.
Closed this in three and a half months, earned
$16,243 in profit, 66% ROI.
Win-win for the borrower, win-win-win for us.
So, as far as our portfolio, these are the
states, obviously, we're working in between.
Some are one-off notes, but once we get these
notes, or these tapes, as we like to call
it from banks, we can cherry-pick.
We want to pick the ones that make sense
for our investors, because they are the ones that
fund the deal, they're the ones interested in seeing
how their returns can be given back to them,
and we want to make sure we can perform.
So, just want to give you guys a little
bit of detail of what it looks like when
we're working it between certain states.
So, how is your capital protected, right?
And this is important.
So, you're in first lien position.
No one comes before you, you get paid first.
We have full control here, right?
So we want to focus on Notes where we
can at least invest at 70% or less to
get that discount, to create that spread and that
opportunity in between.
We're underwriting for worst-case scenarios, so in the event
we have to foreclose.
We are still trying to profit.
We want to make sure things pencil, we want
to make sure we still get a win.
licensed third-party servicing through our partners.
Once again, they handle the communication, they handle the
files, compliance, payments, onboarding, all the paperwork stuff.
They handle it, we just manage it.
Due diligence.
clear to close, title search, BPOs, all those things
are covered through our partners, and even insurance.
Ross Diversified covers that asset, even if something happens
to the property.
So, in summary, you didn't buy a property, you
didn't manage anything.
You just put your money to work.
So, who are we looking for, right?
So, TNC, Take Notes Capital, we're looking for investors
who's looking for above-average returns, right?
People who… who's looking to invest their money, not
wanting to deal with any of the managing parts
of the property.
So these are individuals with cash, savings, that have
money sitting around, don't know where to put it,
earning 4% or less.
Maybe you're a retiree, you have a self-directed RA,
maybe you have a 401K through your job, but
you want to start making money, you want passive
income, you don't know where to look.
Now may be a good opportunity to have a
conversation.
So, tired landlords, these are individuals who's already in
the game.
They're dealing with the 3Ts, the termites, toilets, and
tenants, as I like to call it, but they
want to replace those for just consistent cash flow
without the headaches, and that's understandable.
Private investors, they are actually investing in real estate,
or maybe in some other areas as well, but
they want to get on the debt side of
real estate.
Less overhead, more easy to understand the game, and
they're able to diversify their portfolio to still earn
great cash flow.
Real estate operators, these are the agents that's out
there killing it.
These are the managers that's managing some of the
rentals, and asset managers handling portfolios.
You want to be a part of the game,
you want to invest, can't get access to more
deal flow, this is a great opportunity to see
where mortgage note investing could be a great fit.
So, we are looking for funding partners, but we
do not work with everyone.
And I wanted to be clear, because this may
be a good fit for you.
But…
I may not be a good fit for you,
and you may not be a good fit for
me.
So, with that said.
Let's Talk Notes.
Once again, my name is AJ Dent, principal owner
of Take Notes Capital, real estate investing company.
Go to talkwithajdent.com, you can book there on my
Calendly.
If something here made sense for you, maybe you
want to have a conversation, kind of want to
see more about what this can look like for
you, email me at info@ takenotescapital.com.
And I look forward to investing with you.
Take care.